Preliminary Inventory of the Jan Kowalik papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jan Kowalik papers
1878-1994
Bulk, 1939-1982
93047
Hoover Institution Archives
89 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 9 card file boxes (37.8 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, bibliographies, notes, catalogs, bulletins, biographical data, printed matter, and photographs relating to the post-1939 Polish émigré press, Polish émigré journalists, and notable Polish émigrés in the United States and especially in California. Includes some collected papers of Polish émigrés and records of Polish émigré organizations in the United States.
Kowalik, Jan.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Jan Kowalik was born on August 28, 1910, in Skoczowie, Poland. His birth name was Jan Franciszek Slawiczek, but he was most often known by his pseudonym, Kowalik, or as Jan Franciszek Suchy or Jan Pokrzywa. He is known as a writer, bibliographer, and a poet of the post-World War II era.
Kowalik received his higher education first in the city of Cieszyn, and later in Bielsko-Biała. In 1931 he started working as a teacher in the external studies program at Jagiellonian University. When World War II began, he worked for the resistance movement. In 1944 he was arrested and imprisoned in Germany at a concentration camp in Wrexen.
After the camp’s liberation Kowalik spent a year working as a teacher in a refugee camp in Landau-Waldeck. He then spent the next three years in a tuberculosis sanatorium in Steinatal, first as a patient, and later as an administrator. While working as an administrator at the sanatorium he was also working as a teacher in the hospital’s school and later as a commanding officer at the displaced persons camp in Landau. After Landau, Kowalik worked in the archives of the Sekcja Obozów Koncentracyjnych w Międzynarodowej Komisji Poszukiwań (ITS) in Arolsen, while at the same time nurturing his love for writing and Polish publications. While with ITS, he collaborated on various publications: Kronika, Ostatnie Wiadomości, Słowo Katolickie, and Szlak. He also founded and was the editor of a weekly publication, Polak w Waldeck, which he put out while working as the commanding officer at the displaced persons camp. While in Germany, Kowalik continued his work as a journalist, writer, and poet. His poems were published in two volumes, Ścieżka przez Steinatal, in 1947, and Wiatr w Gałęziach, in 1948.
In 1950, Kowalik moved to the United States, where for two years he worked a series of odd jobs: security guard, window cleaner, night janitor at a cinema, and dishwasher at a restaurant. For three years he worked in the Hoover Library at Stanford University and later resumed his work in the labor force. He dedicated his spare time to his bibliographic work by starting the American-Polish Documentation Studio in California, where his primary work revolved around documenting the historical and bibliographical work of the Polish diaspora, specifically the émigré press. During that time Kowalik also published a great deal. His articles appeared in Kultura, Wiadomości, Oficyna Poetów, Ostatnie Wiadomości, Przegląd Polski, Głos Polski, Prąd, and Związkowiec.
In 1968, Kowalik received an award from the Alfred Jurzkowski Foundation, as well as the Gold Cross of Merit from the Polish President in exile, August Zalewski, for his contributions to Polish history, education, and literature. In 1986 in London, President Edward Raczyński bestowed upon him the medal of the Order of Polonia Restituta, and in 1993 the consul general of Poland in Los Angeles, Jan Szewc, presented him with the medal of the Order of Merit of the Republic of Poland.
Jan Kowalik died on February 11, 2001, in San Jose, California.
Translated from: http://www.bu.kul.pl/jan-kowalik-1910-2001-sylwetka-i-publikacje,art_11355.html
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Jan Kowalik consist of correspondence, writings, bibliographies, notes, catalogs, bulletins, biographical data, printed matter, and photographs relating to the post-1939 Polish émigré press, Polish émigré journalists, and notable Polish émigrés in the United States and especially in California. The papers also include some collected papers of Polish émigrés and records of Polish émigré organizations in the United States.
In addition, the collection contains photographs of the artwork of Hanna Wynerowska (Kali), a Polish-American painter and World War II veteran. The photographs were often sent to Kowalik in the form of greeting cards, along with letters from Kali and her husband. Also included within the collection is a selection of letters from Ferdynand Antoni Ossendowski (Antoni Ferdynand Ossendowski), a Polish journalist and traveler. The folder includes letters of Ossendowski, and photos of him and his second wife, which is of note given the fact that Ossendowski's archives had been destroyed before his death.
Audiotapes.; Journalists.; Poland--Emigration and immigration.; Polish Americans--California.; Polish newspapers--Foreign countries.; Polish people--United States.; Polish periodicals--Foreign countries.
- Correspondence, 1942-1984 (Boxes 1-6)
  - Glos Ameryki (Voice of America): Life of Polish-Americans in California, circa 1970 (Box 1)
  - [Opion?] London, Bednarczyk, Poets and Painters Press, circa 1962 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Regarding publication.
  - Edmund Bojarski, Conradian journal publication, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
  - Prof. Tad Cieplak, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Janusz Laskowksi, 1947 (Box 1)
  - Hrabyk, Klaudiusz, Kronika, 1947-1951 (Box 1)
  - Jaroslaw Horski, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Marek Gordon, 1947-1953 (Box 1)
  - Tadeusz Zagorewicz, 1952-1979 (Box 1)
  - J. Pawlikowski, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Andrzej Brozek, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Stanley Cuba, 1976-1982 (Box 1)
  - Wojciech Zaleski, 1959-1968 (Box 1)
  - Orbis/London, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Witold Zahorski, 1959-1966 (Box 1)
  - Still Strenk, 1961 (Box 1)
  - M. R. Mlotek, 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - Robert Samulski, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Marian Szczepanowski, 1968-1979 (Box 1)
  - Jan Wepsiec, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Janina Zabielska, 1953-1958 (Box 1)
  - Leon Sonka-Dabrowski, 1959-1968 (Box 1)
  - Stanislaw Dabrowski, 1971-1979 (Box 1)
  - Jan Budniewski, 1946-1958 (Box 1)
  - Jozef Bialasiewicz, Kronika, 1947-1948 (Box 1)
  - Leon Dittmar, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Wiktor Londzia and Jan Leszczak, poems, 1947-1955 (Box 1)
  - Glos Polski (Warszunski), publication, 1955-1967 (Box 2)
  - Marian Smieja, 1958-1976 (Box 2)
  - John Switalski, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Wiktor Podski, 1945-1953 (Box 2)
    Includes writings.
  - Stefan Mrozewski, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
    Includes writings and art.
  - Lerski, 1961-1981 (Box 2)
  - Rimma Bogert, 1950-1980 (Box 2)
  - Ellen K. Lee, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Jan Szczepanski, 1961-1969 (Box 2)
  - Lesniewicz-Szczesny, 1960-1970 (Box 2)
    Includes clippings and writings.
  - Swiderski, 1955-1966 (Box 2)
  - The German Polish Institute [?], 1982-1984 (Box 2)
  - R&E Research Associates, 1977-1980 (Box 2)
    Includes writings and pamphlets.
  - Association of Polish-American Journalists, 1951-1976 (Box 2)
  - Stanford University Libraries, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    Regarding the purchase and transfer of books.
  - Halina Sienkiewski [?], 1962-1983 (Box 2)
  - Polish scholarly institutes, 1965-1982 (Box 2)
  - Ostatnie Wiadomosci, 1949-1981 (Box 2)
  - Wiadomosci Londyn, 1947-1981 (Box 2)
  - Wierzynski, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
  - Jerzy Szeptycki, 1947-1958 (Box 2)
  - Tomaszewski, 1955-1980 (Box 2)
  - Woznicki, Migrant Echo, 1972-1980 (Box 2)
  - Zdzislaw Marek, 1956-1967 (Box 2)
  - Jozef Sanocki, 1953-1961 (Box 2)
  - Carlo Badura, 1962-1987 (Box 2)
    Includes photographs, clippings, articles, and journals of Badura, a painter.
  - Wladyslaw Chojnacki, 1951-1982 (Box 3)
  - Adam Ciolkosz, 1969-1973 (Box 3)
  - Maria Danielewiczow, 1956-1977 (Box 3)
  - Polish writers in exile, 1960-1962 (Box 3)
    Includes letters from Rostworowski, Milosz, and others (not very legible).
  - Benedict Heydenkorn, Zwiazkowiec Toronto, 1960-1981 (Box 3)
  - Leon Koczy, 1955-1967 (Box 3)
  - Polskie Towarzystwo Naukowe na Obczyznie, 1959-1982 (Box 3)
  - Syndicate of Polish Journalists in Germany, 1946-1948 (Box 3)
  - Jan Bielatowicz, 1956-1965 (Box 3)
  - Jakub Hofman, 1955-1963 (Box 3)
  - Stanislaw Zybala, Glos Polski, 1950-1962 (Box 3)
  - Edward Kasimiec, 1977-1981 (Box 3)
  - Wojciech Zalewski, 1977-1980 (Box 3)
  - Orchard Lake Schools, 1962-1982 (Box 3)
  - Polish American Historical Association, 1963-1982 (Box 3)
  - Jacek Przygoda, 1959-1980 (Box 3)
  - Polski Instytut Naukowy w Kanadzie, 1978 (Box 3)
  - The Polish Museum of America (Chicago), 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Wanda Tomczykowska, 1969-1983 (Box 3)
  - Radio Free Europe, 1954-1956 (Box 3)
  - Jan Broda, 1947-1979 (Box 4)
  - Szwede Slavic Books, 1960-1980 (Box 4)
  - Marion Coleman, 1959-1977 (Box 4)
  - Lewicki, Stanislaw Ludwick, 1952-1958 (Box 4)
  - Alfred Deblin and Herman Kesten, 1947-1951 (Box 4)
  - Czeslaw Grycz, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
  - Waclaw Iwaniuk, 1963-1977 (Box 4)
  - Jerzy Bielski, 1951-1959 (Box 4)
  - Plachy, 1942-1963 (Box 4)
  - Ryszard Reiss-Czemplik, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
  - Nina Westall-Eisenberg, 1948 (Box 4)
  - Adolf Badura, 1947-1968 (Box 4)
  - Ryszard Dymbinski, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Stanislaw Gliwa, 1968-1983 (Box 4)
  - Czeslaw M. A. Horain, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Polish Institute of Arts and Sciences New York, 1959-1980 (Box 4)
    Includes publications and clippings.
  - Bohdan Deresiewicz, 1977-1979 (Box 4)
  - Waclaw Stefan Flisinski, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Jan Fryling, 1959-1969 (Box 4)
  - Katolicki Uniwersytet Lubelski, 1975-1981 (Box 4)
  - Krzyzanowski, 1961-1978 (Box 4)
  - Terelicki, 1956-1978 (Box 5)
  - Veritas Foundation, 1966-1967 (Box 5)
  - Weintrallb, 1966-1979 (Box 5)
  - University of Minnesota, 1972-1980 (Box 5)
    Regarding the microfilm archives projects on Poles in America.
  - Byrnes Robert, Mid-European Studies Center, 1954-1955 (Box 5)
  - Jozef Pilsudski Institute, 1959-1970 (Box 5)
  - Osrodek Badan Prasoznawczych, 1973-1983 (Box 5)
  - Kamil Kantak, 1957-1962 (Box 5)
  - Twirek, 1957-1964 (Box 5)
  - Zaeadowski, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
  - The Kosciuszko Foundation, 1971-1977 (Box 5)
  - Godlenski, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Polska Biblioteka w Paryzu, 1959-1971 (Box 5)
  - Alliance College, 1951-1979 (Box 5)
  - Szylkarski, 1946-1949 (Box 5)
  - Jur St [?], 1946-1949 (Box 5)
  - Oszelda, 1947-1979 (Box 5)
  - Lednicki, 1942-1958 (Box 5)
  - Koper, 1947-1976 (Box 5)
  - Lubomirscy, 1947-1948 (Box 5)
  - Stnominski, 1949-1953 (Box 5)
  - Bibloteka Narodowa w Warszawie, 1957-1970 (Box 5)
  - Trzeciak, 1959-1961 (Box 5)
  - Trypnicki, 1955-1957 (Box 5)
  - Tolczynska Dietrich, 1977 (Box 5)
  - Szczesniak, 1956-1961 (Box 5)
  - John Pitton, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Pawlikowski, 1959-1965 (Box 5)
  - Paszkowski, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Olipra, 1939-1957 (Box 5)
    Includes biographical sketch regarding his work.
  - Mlotek, 1961-1967 (Box 5)
  - Jezewski, 1955-1976 (Box 5)
  - Riccardo Casiniro Lewanski, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Godlewski, 1974-1982 (Box 6)
  - Vincenty Zurski, 1977-1980 (Box 6)
    Includes reports.
  - Kultura, Giedroyc I and II, 1948-1959, 1960-1983 (Box 6)
  - Janta, 1955-1983 (Box 6)
    Includes printed articles.
  - Bound copy of Felieton z Ameryki, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Bound copy of poems by father Jan Twardowski, circa 1970 (Box 6)
  - Bound copy of Piesn Niepodlegla, by Czeslaw Milosz, circa 1942 (Box 6)
  - Bound copy of One Man’s Journey, by Suzy Hagstrom, 1974 (Box 6)
  - Krauze, 1958-1961 (Box 6)
  - Jozef Mackiewicz, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Tad Borowicz, 1957-1960 (Box 6)
  - Jerzy Grot-Kwasniewski, 1959-1978 (Box 6)
  - Pawel Jasike, 1970-1973 (Box 6)
  - Bem (kolo zolnierzy), 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - H. M. Malak, 1948-1978 (Box 6)
    Includes photos and printed matter.
  - Karol Kleszczynski, periodical publication, 1966 (Box 6)
  - Jan Kraniec, 1948-1984 (Box 6)
- Writings and bound publications (Box 7)
  Mostly writings, bound publications, and articles, including writings by Chojnacki and others, bibliographies of Polish works or works by Polish writers, and bibliographic sources on the history of the Polish press abroad. Includes materials on a Polish Solidarity conference at the University of Virginia, 1982; additions to the YIVO Institute for Jewish Research (partially in Hebrew); and notes and a photocopy of Herbert Hoover's address from 1919 at the Palace Hotel in San Francisco.
- Printed matter and writings (Box 8)
  Material regarding the shipment of Kowalik’s Polish press archives to the West Germany Society of Christ Archives, as well as some information on a Solidarity writing house.
- Printed matter (Box 9)
  Bound printed matter, bibliography of the Polish diaspora, and some underground publications. Includes the publication Harcestwo Polskie w Kanadzie.
- Printed matter (Box 10)
  Includes Polish-American History in Northern California, Harcerstwo Polskie w Kanadzie, Swiatowy Scouting, Bibliografia prasy Polskiej, and Orzel Bialy Archive Material, among others. Also includes the collected works of Buczewski, and a binder titled "Ethnicity, Who’s Who in Northern California."
- Printed matter (Box 11)
  Includes 1989 issues of Przeglad Polonijny, Polish Press Abroad 1939 Vol II D and G, World Index of Polish Periodicals Vol. I, and materials regarding the history of the Polish press abroad.
- Printed matter (Box 12)
  Includes Polish Press Abroad 1939 Vol II F; subject lists of the Hoover Archives on Polish and Middle Eastern holdings, 1948-1987; and World Index of Polish Periodicals Vol. II.
- Printed matter and bound writings, 1960-1978 (Box 13)
- Printed matter and bound writings (Box 14)
  Includes bibliographies and some loose materials on Hoover holdings, circa 1967, as well as bound pamphlets, correspondence, communiqués, and reports. The bound volumes are labeled with letters of the alphabet, and in some instances the labels match correspondents.
- Printed matter and bound writings (Box 15)
  Includes some loose papers, circa 1964-1968, as well as bound pamphlets, correspondence, communiqués, and reports. The bound volumes are labeled with letters of the alphabet, and in some instances the labels match correspondents.
- Correspondence, printed matter, and writings (Box 16)
  Materials are arranged by last name and likely came from a larger folder titled "Journalists." Materials also include biographical articles and sketches of these journalists; Kowalik corresponded with most of them in the 1960s.
- Printed matter and writings (Box 17)
  Includes a folder labeled "Polish Press (USA and Abroad), 1939-1977" and three bound books of writings, articles, and printed matter.
- Polish press abroad, 1939-1977 (Boxes 18-19)
- Miscellaneous (Box 20)
  Loose items and bound notebooks. One large notebook contains issues of a bulletin titled Centrum Jana Pawla II, 1979-1985, copies of bound writings and bibliographies, and spiral notebooks of Polish-German bibliographies.
- Correspondence, writings, printed matter, and information on Polish Radio in San Francisco (Box 21)
  Materials relating to the Polish press, circa 1980.
- Poles and Polish organizations in California (Box 22)
  Writings, correspondence, and printed matter.
- Journalists and Poles in California, 1950-1980 (Box 23)
  Printed matter, writings, articles, notes, and correspondence.
- Miscellaneous (Box 24)
  Two folders labeled "Journalists," a continuation from the previous box. Includes loose bulletins, articles, printed matter, and some correspondence; an envelope of correspondence, clippings, writings, printed matter, and photos from 1925; and a binder titled "Polish Day Committee for the 1939 Golden Globe International Exposition," consisting mostly of correspondence (1938-1939).
- Miscellaneous (Box 25)
  Binder titled "Fund for Victims of War in Poland" (correspondence and receipts, some newspaper clippings from 1939); a card file from a meeting in 1975; materials (including correspondence and reports) from a Polish group in the Bay Area; a Stanislaw Blonski folder (clippings, photos, and correspondence, circa 1970); and a F. [Ferdynand] A. [Antoni] Ossendowski folder (clippings, correspondence, pamphlets, 1878-1945). A second Ossendowski folder consists of photos (1878 and 1914), correspondence, and a booklet, Na Spotaknie Ludziom z AK.
- Oversize material (Box 26)
  Diary with an alphabetical list of Polish periodicals, 1951-1963; cash ledgers; a catalog of periodicals in Polish or relating to Poland; a folder of materials on the Warsaw Uprising; a Prebski folder with photos, correspondence, and clippings, 1963; an American Relief for Poland list of cash contributions, 1948; and a mounted print of "Reception for General Haller by Polish Colony of S. F., Palace Hotel, October 18, 1923."
- Printed matter and writings (Box 27)
  Includes a binder titled "Polish Bibliography Abroad PERSONAL BIBLIOGRAPHY."
- Newspapers and bulletins, circa 1970 (Box 28)
- Miscellaneous (Box 29)
  Printed matter, correspondence, writings, and an interview with Jan Kowalik talking about his bio-bibliographic project, circa 1980.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1970-1986 (Box 30)
- Photographs (Box 31)
  Includes some photos matted to create make-shift albums, as well as a photo album from the early 1940s, with photographs of the Anders Army soldiers in Tel-Aviv and Cairo.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1942-1987 (Box 32)
- Miscellaneous, 1950-1970 (Box 33)
  Bylaws, journals, bulletins, writings, articles, news clippings, notebook/address book, and correspondence.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1950 (Box 34)
- Correspondence and printed matter, 1984-1994 (Box 35)
  Includes bibliographies and bound journals.
- Miscellaneous (Box 36)
  Bound volumes, newspapers, and correspondence, as well as a booklet of poems.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1913-1950 (Box 37)
- Sound recordings (Box 38)
  Compact sound cassette tapes and magnetic tapes, some with recordings of speeches and lectures.
- Writings, printed matter, and photographs, circa 1950 (Box 39)
  Photographs are mostly of turbines, with a couple depicting Prince Poniatowski.
- Writings and printed matter, circa 1970 (Box 40)
  Includes a file on Zawodny.
- Printed matter, circa 1940 (Box 41)
  Includes a manuscript regarding Mother Teresa, documents relating to the Polish press, journals, and bulletins.
- Writings and printed matter (Box 42)
  Includes two journals of writings and clippings regarding motherhood, biographies of Polish journalists abroad, military periodical publications, and institutional civilian publications.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1949-1990 (Boxes 43-45)
- Miscellaneous, 1940-1980 (Box 46)
  Includes a binder of personal documents (marriage certificate, birth certificate, relocation papers); two paper albums with unidentified photos (circa 1940); folder of correspondence with Hanna Weynerowski-Kali and her husband Henryk, including signed photos of her artwork (circa 1980); correspondence (1965-1980); binder of Kowalik letters to Rev. Prof. Wojciech Sojka (1956-1976), including biographical chronology of Kowalik (in Polish).
- Miscellaneous, circa 1980 (Box 47)
  Includes writings, printed matter, Rudolf Korwin folder (correspondence and writings), spiral notebooks filled with words (makeshift dictionary), loose correspondence, note about Kali, and a copy of a christening certificate.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1990 (Box 48)
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1952 (Box 49)
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1980 (Box 50)
- Walter Zawojski, circa 1950 (Box 51)
  Includes material outlining the work of Walter Zawojski, graphic artist and associate of Stanford, as well as pamphlets, writings, and correspondence.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1977-1982 (Box 52)
- Sound recordings (Boxes 53-54)
  Compact sound cassette tapes, and magnetic tapes (circa 1972), of talks, gallery shows, music, seminars, conferences, and religious broadcasts.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1990 (Box 55)
- Miscellaneous, circa 1985 (Box 56)
  Writings, printed matter, a file on Pope John Paul II, bibliographies, correspondence, bulletins, and photographs of Kowalik and his wife, as well as members of the Carnegie Institute in Washington.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1960 (Box 57)
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1970 (Box 58)
  Includes press coverage on the Pope's visit to California.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, circa 1980 (Box 59)
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1912, 1927 (Box 60)
- Miscellaneous, circa 1970 (Box 61)
  Watercolor paintings, a file titled "Immigration History Minnesota University Research Center," a file on censorship in the press, a file on Wojciech Chojnacki writings,a file on Terlecki, and a file on the Polish Boy Scouts (Harcerze).
- Writings and printed matter, 1939-1983 (Box 62)
  Includes material on Polish émigré press in Britain and some religious music pamphlets.
- Correspondence, writings, and printed matter, 1953-1989 (Box 63)
- Printed matter, circa 1945 (Box 64)
- Writings and printed matter, circa 1980 (Box 65)
- Writings and printed matter (Box 66)
  Catalogs of Polish books, articles on Polish press abroad, manuscript on Teodor Palichleb, printed poems, bulletins, and a pamphlet on Kali.
- Miscellaneous, 1987-1993 (Box 67)
  Bibliographies, materials on Polish press in world libraries, bulletins, clippings, articles, newspapers, Polish publishers in post-WWII Germany (1945-1950), and a Polish colony in California. Also includes documents on the acting career of Helena Modejska.
- Miscellaneous (Box 68)
  Includes two issues of Lazik (1944-1945), folder with information on the oldest Polish periodicals abroad, a publication titled Krzyze Kapliczki Przydrozne, On the Trail Through Noremberg, and a map of Silesia (in German, circa 1952).
  Additional materials include writings by Zenon Bouczewski, a letter by Mrs. Carrie M. Webb regarding Al J. Gardisky (circa 1971), letters from Wolfgang Von Hildenbrant (1948-1949), Illustrirte Zeitung Leipzig (circa 1941), writings, publications, Nazi party publications (Karl C. Von Loesch, 1931-1940), a plaque from the Polish Arts and Culture foundation honoring Kowalik for his bibliographic work (July 1990), a 1949 German map, bronze medal Potulice (1932-1982), travel journal, medals from 1966 and 1968, photos of Kowalik with family, and a charcoal and pastel drawing.
- Miscellaneous (Box 69)
  Kowalik’s address book from 1957, small box of various identification cards, Dziennik Zolnieza issues (1942), printed matter (1916-1963), certificate of Wanda Black for her help in building the Pilsudski home, photographs of the Poznan archives, and a letter from the Hoover Institution regarding the Magna Carta exhibit in 1978.
- Miscellaneous (Box 70)